Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Correspondence, 1959-1997, Series 1; Boxes 1-56
  - Children's correspondence, 1961-1996, Subseries 1.4; Boxes 48-52; OP1
    The subseries consists of correspondence written by children in response to his children's books from 1961-1996. Many letters which include drawings, were sent to Hughes from entire classrooms of children, particluarly relating to The Iron Man (1985), and the subsequent animated movie Iron Giant (1999) and its sequel, The Iron Women (1993).
    - 1961-1978 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - 1985 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - 1986 January-June (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - 1986 July-December (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - 1987 January-March (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - 1987 April-December (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 1988 January-June (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - 1988 July-November (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - 1988 December (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - 1989 January-April (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 1989 May-December (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - 1992 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - 1993 January-April (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 1993 May-December (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - 1994 January-February (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - 1994 March-April (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 1994 June-December (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 1995 January-April (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - 1995 May-August (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 1995 September-December (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 1996 January-February (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - 1996 March-April (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1996 May-December (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Undated: re The Iron Man (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Undated: re The Iron Man (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Undated: re How the Whale Became and others (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Undated: Misc. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Oversized children's drawings re: The Iron Man (Box OP1)
  - Ted Hughes' correspondence, 1957-1997, Subseries 1.5; Boxes 53-56
    The subseries consists of correspondence written by Ted Hughes from 1957-1996. The subseries also includes copies of letters that Hughes wrote to Sylvia Plath's mother, Aurelia Plath from 1963-1969 from the Lilly Library at Indiana University.
    Arranged in chronological order. Undated letters are arranged by the last name of recipient; when last names are not present, the undated correspondence is arranged by the first name of the recipient. Undated correspondence with no designated recipient is arranged by subject at the end of this subseries.
    - Chronological
    - [Fall 1957]; 1960-1969 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 1970-1978 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - 1988 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - January-March 1989 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - April-June 1989 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - July-December 1989 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - 1990 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - January-June 1991 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - July-September 1991 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - October-December 1991 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - January-March 1992 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - April-June 1992 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - July-September 1992 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - October-December 1992 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - January-March 1993 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - April-June 1993 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - July-September 1993 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - October-December 1993 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - January-March 1994 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - April-June 1994 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - July-September 1994 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - October-December 1994 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - January-March 1995 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - April-June 1995 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - July-December 1995 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - 1996 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Plath, Aurelia, 1963-1969 [from Lilly Library, Sylvia Plath papers, do not photocopy without permission from Lilly] (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Undated - Alphabetical by recipient
    - A., P. [re: Peter Brooks] (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Alvarez, Al [fragment] (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Baker, Kenneth (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Bishop, Nick (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Boyanowsky, Victoria, Letter of recommendation [Simon Fraser University] (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Bruford, Rose (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Brooks, Peter (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Kerry [Sacred Earth] (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Burrows, Ms. (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Butcher, Tim (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Clinton, Sir Gerald (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Cox, Brian (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Dartmouth College (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Davids, Roy (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Day, David, Letter of recommendation (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Day, Hugo, Letter of recommendation (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Doolan, Moira F. (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - Edward, John [fragment] (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Eliot, Valerie (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Evans, Caroline and Matthew (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Gammage, Nick (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Gowrie, Lord Grey (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - Grafton the Duke and Duchess of (Hugh and Fortune) (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - Gunn, Thom, Letter of recommendation [Macarthur Fellowship] (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Hamilton, Ian (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Hart, Josephine (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - Heaney, Seamus (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Heseltine, Anne and Michael (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - Holub, Miroslav (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - Hudson, Sir Hal (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - Hughes, David (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - Hunter, David, Letter of recommendation (Box 55, Folder 34)
    - Kermode, Frank (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - Kustow, Michael (Box 55, Folder 36)
    - Letter to Editor [newspaper unknown] (Box 55, Folder 37)
    - Letter to Editor, The Sunday Times (Box 55, Folder 38)
    - Linklater, N.V. (Box 55, Folder 39)
    - Lowenstein, Tom, Letter of recommendation (Box 55, Folder 40)
    - Malpass, Katie (Box 55, Folder 41)
    - Murphy, Richard (Box 55, Folder 42)
    - Newman, Mr. (Box 55, Folder 43)
    - P., Mrs. C. (Box 55, Folder 44)
    - P., P. (Box 55, Folder 45)
    - [Perloff, Marjorie] (Box 55, Folder 46)
    - Plath, Jenny and Susan (Box 55, Folder 47)
    - Prince of Wales, Prince Charles (Box 55, Folder 48)
    - Pudney, John (Box 55, Folder 49)
    - Radcliffe, Michael (Box 55, Folder 50)
    - Raine, Craig (Box 55, Folder 51)
    - Rose, Jacqueline (Box 55, Folder 52)
    - Rudolf, Henry [about] (Box 55, Folder 53)
    - Ruscoe, John (Box 55, Folder 54)
    - Saatchi, Joseph and Maurice (Box 55, Folder 55)
    - Seymour, Miranda (Box 55, Folder 56)
    - Solataroff, Ted (Box 55, Folder 57)
    - Soyinka, Wole (Box 55, Folder 58)
    - Spender, Natasha (Box 55, Folder 59)
    - Tardios, George, Letter of recommendation (Box 55, Folder 60)
    - Thatcher, Margaret (Box 55, Folder 61)
    - Walker, Mr. (Box 55, Folder 62)
    - Walsh, John (Box 55, Folder 63)
    - Weissbort, Daniel, Letter of Recommendation [Guggenheim Award] (Box 55, Folder 64)
    - White, Eric (Box 55, Folder 65)
    - Wylie, Mrs. (Box 55, Folder 66)
    - Undated - Alphabetical by recipient's first name
    - [?], Alan (Box 55, Folder 67)
    - [?], Anne (Box 55, Folder 68)
    - [?], Charles (Box 55, Folder 69)
    - [?], Clifford (Box 55, Folder 70)
    - [?], Dea (Box 55, Folder 71)
    - [?], Desmond (Box 55, Folder 72)
    - [?], Eric (Box 55, Folder 73)
    - [?], Gordon (Box 55, Folder 74)
    - [?], Hubert (Box 55, Folder 75)
    - [?], Hugh (Box 55, Folder 76)
    - [?], Karl (Box 55, Folder 77)
    - [?], Martin (Box 55, Folder 78)
    - [?], Michael (Box 55, Folder 79)
    - [?], Peter (Box 55, Folder 80)
    - [?], Ruth (Box 55, Folder 81)
    - [?], Simon (Box 55, Folder 82)
    - [?], Sir Philip (Box 55, Folder 83)
    - [?], Siv (Box 55, Folder 84)
    - [?], Teddy (Box 55, Folder 85)
    - [?], Val (Box 55, Folder 86)
    - [?], Victor (Box 55, Folder 87)
    - Undated - Unknown recipient
    - Unknown [re: American edition of Sylvia Plath's writings] (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Unknown [re: Anne Stevenson's Bitter Fame] (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Unknown [re: Appearance at which he will read Nightingale's Nest] (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Unknown [re: Arvon Foundation] (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Unknown [re: Children's poetry contest comments and grades] (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Unknown [re: Daniel Weissbort poems] (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Unknown [re: David Pease] (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Unknown [re: Donald Davie - Arvon Foundation Poetry Competition] (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Unknown [re: Dylan Thomas commemorative plaque at Westminster Abbey] (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Unknown [re: Fishing] (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Unknown [re: Dr. G.H. Davis' article on local otter population] (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Unknown [re: Hughes' comments on another poet's collection] (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Unknown [re: Hughes' comments on first writing] (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Unknown [re: Hughes' comments on work since 1989] (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Unknown [re: Iron Man play] (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Unknown [re: Jacqueline Rose's The Haunting of Sylvia Plath] (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Unknown [re: John Moat and John Fairfax's The Way to Write] (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Unknown [re: Journalism on Sylvia Plath (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Unknown [re: the Laureate] (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Unknown [re: the Laureate and expenses] (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Unknown [re: Modern Poetry in Translation] (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Unknown [re: Philip Larkin's death] (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Unknown [re: Proposed playwright competition] (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Unknown [re: School appearances, rescheduling] (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Unknown [re: Seamus Heaney, working on poetry competition] (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - Unknown [re: Sean Hill, Catey Chef of Year Award] (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Unknown miscellanous letters and fragments (Box 56, Folder 27)
- Writings by Ted Hughes, circa 1949-1990, Series 2; Boxes 57-86; OP2-58a; 105-107; OBV1
  The series contains writings by Ted Hughes including notebooks containing manuscript poems; collected and uncollected manuscripts and typescripts; and manuscript and typescript prose, scripts and librettos, writings for children, and translations.
  Organized into seven subseries: (2.1) Notebooks, (2.2) Collected poems, (2.3) Uncollected poems (both general and those that Hughes grouped as "Crow Poems"), (2.4) Prose, (2.5) Scripts and librettos, (2.6) Children's writings, and (2.7) Translations.
  - Notebooks, circa 1949-1995, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 57-58; OBV1
    The subseries contains notebooks of Ted Hughes from ca. 1949-ca. 1990. The notebooks include titled and untitled drafts of published and unpublished poems and prose, a few diary entries and autobiographical notes from ca. 1968 August [Notebook 9], and astrological charts [Notebook 3 and 28]. Notebooks that contained poems associated with a single work may be found with that work in other subseries within Series 2. The notebooks in this subseries have been assigned numbers to facilitate access.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - [Notebook 1], Notebook (torn in half), n.d., [ca. 1949-1966], 62 pp. Multiple untitled manuscript drafts including an untitled short story ("The address to the public...,") followed by "A dreamed story: August 19th." Verso of notebook pages contain multiple poem drafts including "Against Larks," "The Black Oak," "Ode to Indolence," "The Fallen Violin," and A Wind Flashes the Grass." (Box OBV1)
    - [Notebook 2], Notebook (disbound with additional loose sheets), n.d., [ca. 1956-1957], 16 pp. Multiple untitled manuscript drafts including "The Decay of Vanity," "Macaw and Little Miss," "The Hawk in the Rain," "Stories about you bastard English" ["The Calum-makers"], "Six Young Men," "Meeting," "Parlour-Piece," "Two Wise Generals," "The Retired Colonel," "Relic," "Pennies in April," "Dick Straightup," "Childbirth," "Griefs for Dead Soldiers," "Roarers in a Ring," "The Burning of the Brothel," "Soliloquy of a Misanthrope," "The Martyrdom of Bishop Farrar," "Invitation to a Dance," "Billet-Doux," "The Casualty," "Esther's Tomcat," "The Horses of the Sun," "Wilfred Owen's Photographs," "Death of a Prophet," "Cat and Mouse," and other unidentified poems and prose works. (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - [Notebook 3], Notebook (disbound with additional loose sheets), n.d., [ca. 1957], 26 pp. Notes on the lives of H.C. Anderson, the Bröntes, Columbus, Parnell, Houdini Walter Raleigh, William Blake, and others. [Accession 98-07-14] (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - [Notebook 4], Tudor triplicate notebook (partial, back cover and many pages missing), n.d., [ca. 1955-56], 64 leaves. Includes drafts for "The Vampire," titled and untitled drafts of unpublished poems including "The new child wonders, and is dazed, and cries...," "Ballad of Vampirized Man," "Man Condemned," "Ballad of the Church Devil," "The Man Who Dreamed He Murdered His Wife." Also includes first drafts of published short stories "How the Whale Became," "How the Hyena Became," and "O'Kelly's Angel," and partial draft of the fable "The Calum Makers." This notebook also includes several diagrams (probably unrelated to poems), and several astrological charts. (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - [Notebook 5], Loose sheets from a small Challenge Duplicate Notebook, n.d., [ca. 1960-1967], 9 leaves, 18 pages, mostly disbound. Contains titled and untitled drafts of published [in Recklings] and unpublished poems: "Song of Songs," "Wherever I tread, the grass cries in fury...," "You now grow slowly lighter...," "Bombing Berlin," "Toll of the Air-Raids" [published title "Toll"], "Poor Men in the Public Bar" "The Bar-room TV blinks..." "The T.V. splashes on ..." "Patient Poor Men" and "Patient Men" [variant drafts of published poem: "Public Bar T.V."], "Here Come the Bells," "If God is Rejectable...," "Could God be rejectable?..." "The Sunk Swan's Nest," "Pounding and Posting," "The Eon of Lizards" [published title: "The Era of Giant Lizards"], "The murderer's victim studied his corpse...," "A pebble of the flood had seen...," "Between Westminster and sunstruck St. Paul's...," "Heatwave," "All the heroes end the same way," "Camouflage is death's fifth column...," and "The greened or blacked eyelids and all that torn hair..." (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - [Notebook 6], Duplicate notebook with missing covers, n.d., [ca. 1964-1967] 112 pages. Includes titled and untitled drafts of published and unpublished poems: "Gnat Psalm" [published Wodwo 1967], "Three Legends," "Invocation of Crow," "Crow-keep," "The Totem Oak," "I saw the black ball, badly punctured...," "The infinity of womb failures...," "Crow in the Nursery," "Crow and Mama," "When the pistol muzzle oozing blue vapour..." [published title: "That Moment"], "In the beginning was scream..." [published title "Lineage"], "The nothingness began the mirror / Crow looks into looking far...," "Crowhole," "The parson's eye stopped among black letters...," "When God hammered Crow / He made gold..." [published title "Crow's Song of Himself"], "Crow Goes Out to Play" [published title "In the Little Girl's Angel Gaze"], "Crowblack" [published title: "Crow Was So Much Blacker"], "Crow Struggles to Light," "Crow Fights for Lebensraum," "A Prank" [published title: "A Childish Prank"], "First Lesson" [published title: "Crow's First Lesson"], "Magical Dangers," "Baby Crow Encounters Space," "Crow and the Star," "Crow Immunised," "Crow's Ego" [published title "Crowego"], "Crow Hears Fate Knock on the Door," "Crow's Fast" [dated "3rd Sept" in Hughes's hand], "Creation quaked voices..." [published title: "Crow Tyrannosaurus"], "There were the cars, noses to the promenade rail / Staring at the ancient sea...," "Words came with life insurance policies..." [published title: "The Battle of Osfrontalis"], "Crow decided to try words..." [published title: Crow Goes Hunting"], "There came news of a word" [published title: "A Disaster"], "Fairy Tales," "Crow realized God loved him..." [published title: "Crow's Theology"], "Crow's Quill," "Crow Alights," "Crow's Advent," "How Crow Learned to Fly," "The Door," "Crow Gets His Regalia," "Salamander," "Crow's Wars," "Crow and the Birds," "Crow's Charade" [published title: "The Black Beast"], "The King of ... and ..." [published title: "The King of Carrion"], "Crow's Cry," "A Bout," "Ballad of William the Rhymer," "Truth and Crow," "Fragment of Smashing Tablets" [published title: "Fragment of Ancient Tablet"], "Crow's Note Play" [published title: "Notes for A Little Play"], "God was sick...," "The Air in Its Prison," "Conjuring in Heaven," "Flogged lame with legs..." [published title: "A Kill"], "Bad Monuments," "Crow's Nerve Fails," "Exam at the Womb Door" [published title: "Examination at the Womb Door"], "Crow Sends Truth and Nothing Out" [published title: "Truth Kills Everybody"], "Astronomical Crow," "The wolf cried 'wolf-wolf' in a wail...," "Oedipus Crow," "Crow Outlawed," "Crow's Battle Fury," "Crow Goes Into Battle" [published title: "Crow's Battle Fury"], "Truth Kills Everybody," "That Crow on the elm's limb...," "The ignorant crow is watching the earth...," "Lonely crow created the gods for playmates...," "Crow, lonely with only space..." [published title: "Crow's Playmates"], "Carrion Tiresias Examines the Sacrifice," "When Crow was white he decided the sea was white too...," "Crow Hears the Sea," "Crow and the Sea," "Come from the sea," "O Littleblood..." [published title: "Littleblood"], "Crow Sickened," "From the Ancient ...," "The tiger...," "Crow and Justice" [published title: "Crowcolour"], "And God said to man...," "This moment / a man...," "Somewhere in the world - a man falling...," "Crow and Stone," "The Word in the Wilderness," and "Crow Fails" ["'Look' said God 'I've had an inspiration...'"] (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - [Notebook 7], Small notebook with brown cover: "Vicar's Hill Boldre" printed on front cover, and "Lloyd Dictation" handwritten on front cover, n.d., [ca. 1964-68], 6 leaves, 3.5 pages. Contains one page of descriptive notes for Gaudete, one page of draft notes for the introduction to Johnny Panic and the Bible of Dreams by Plath's Poems." (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - [Notebook 8], Challenge Duplicate Book, n.d., [ca. 1965-1966], ca. 200 pp. Multiple titled and untitled drafts of published and unpublished poems including "Public Servant," "Carol," "A Loss," "Heirloom," "Roman September," "Ground of Being," "Brother's 1st Dream," "Doodle on the Blotter," "God is Love," "A Retirement," "Woman's Weeping," "News," "Revelation," "A Dancer," "Little Cantata," "Lines for Yorick's Skull," "The Hunter," "Beowulf's Banner," "Baby Cries," "Spare Soliloquy for Hamlet," "Conversion," "A Gnat Dance," "The Black Oak" [variant title for "Your Tree-Your Oak"], "Wings," "The Bear," "It is not enough just to exist," "Gnats," "A Wind Flashes the Grass," "The Fallen Violin," "Gnat Psalm," "Blood and Karma" [variant title for "Karma"], "Postcard from Connemara," "Second Glance at a Jaguar," "Episode from a Fairy Tale," "Crow's Totem," "Larks," "Corporal Crow Goes Into Battle," "Violet," "Buttercup," "Science Lessons," "Metamorphoses," "Skylarks," "The Red Carpet," "The Writer," "Dog Days on the Black Sea," "Scapegoats and Rabies," "In Memorium," "Migration," "Genesis of Many Consequences," "To W.H. Auden," "A Near Miss," "Exit," "Poetry Festival," "How to write verse," "Why Write?," "The Oak," and other unidentified poems. Notebook also includes six pages of notes for Wodwo (originally titled "The Rain-Horse"). Two additional untitled poems ("How many helpers...," and "Who is that person...") [possibly about Sylvia Plath]. On back of page 97 written upside down is beginning draft of "The Tender Place," Birthday Letters (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - [Notebook 9], Notebook with color illustration of birds on front cover, titled "Books for Notes" on back cover, n.d., [ca. 1965-1966], 4.5 pages plus 10 blank leaves, includes notes for "Dylan Thomas's Letters" a review of The Selected Letters of Dylan Thomas, [published in The New Statesman (1966)]. Also includes a brief notation: "Plays - some terribly simple action - sustained by its music and intensity. An atomic action - in close-up." Notebook includes two pages of notes written by a young child. (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - [Notebook 10], Notebook (lacking covers with additional loose sheets laid in), n.d., [ca. 1967-1968], ca. 110 pp. Outline of Crow sequence ("Creation & Invocation of Crow"), along with multiple titled and untitled manuscript drafts, including "Lineage," "Crowego," "Baby Crow Ponders the Stars," "Baby Crow Encounters Time and Egg, Studies a Crystal Ball," "The Guardian Angel," "Upstart Crow," "Fragment of an Ancient Tablet," "Examination at the Womb Door," "Crow's ... Play," "Crow and Dust," and other unidentified poems. Also includes two diary entries from 1968 August and other autobiographical notes (pp. 76-77, 84, and 92) and notes on poetry. (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - [Notebook 11], Spiral bound shorthand notebook), n.d., [ca. 1968-1969], ca. 110 pp. Contains multiple titled and untitled poem and prose drafts, including "Into the City" [from prose narrative of Crow], and itemized expenses from March 9th to April 5th, 1968, and an April 1969 journal from Hughes's trip to Ireland containing his thoughts regarding Assia Wevill's death. (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - [Notebook 12], Large, hard-covered black notebook, 64 leaves, list of bird names [titles of poems] written on inside front cover. Contains autograph manuscripts of bird poems [most published in A Primer of Birds (1981), many also first published in special copies of the first edition of Cave Birds (1975)]. Additionally, there are some typescripts and typescript carbons tucked into the notebook. Includes titled and untitled drafts of poems including "Pheasants," "The Hen," "Swan" [published title: "Swans"], "Buzzard," "Swallow," "Treecreeper," "The Moorhen," "Wren," "The Nightingale," "Evening Thrush," "Kingfisher," "The Macaw" [published title "A Macaw"], "A Sparrow Hawk," "Snipe," "Shrike," "Magpie," and "Heron" [published title: "The Heron"]. Also contains a draft of "Song Against the White Owl" [published in Crow Speaks (1971)], and unpublished poems: "Cormornats," "Two Marabou Storks," and fragment of "Flamingo." (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - [Notebook 13], Challenge Duplicate Notebook, partial, with blue covers, many pages missing, one page dated in Hughes's hand "10th March 1970" [ca. 1970], 10 leaves, 10 pages, bound. Two unknown addresses written on first page. Contains a few notes for Prometheus on His Crag and titled and untitled drafts of published and unpublished poems: "There is a man / When the dentist...," "Man comes running complaining -- / Behind him his...," "Niagara Falls," "His cave in the moon...," page titled "Prometheus" [includes several lines of holograph notes], "Prometheus on His Crag" [written at the top of a blank page], 1/2 page of notes relating to Prometheus and Pandora, list of six words in English and their translations, fragment: "So here's my soul ye - is it this that or that / What is it?" (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - [Notebook 14], Fragment of notebook, disbound, burn marks at upper right edge, n.d., [ca. 1970s], 31 pages. Contains untitled drafts: "We were safe...," "Our ... of time...," "Where was she laid?" "The ... doves combing the April ????," "Now the log suffers its fullness," "A buzzard's soaring..." [drafts with variant first line], "What would be lovely to care not...," "English as I am, a leaf on the old oak," "Like a tree riven by 3 visions...," "We were safe," "The pebbles came from the river," "By the time he could no longer see that she was only half handsome...,") and "Inside it a velvety ..." (Box 57, Folder 13)